<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Linux is my way</title>
    
    
    
    <link>./post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Linux is my way</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Emin Yaren</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="./post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash script for ffmpeg</title>
      <link>./post/batchffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/batchffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Using Ffmpeg is very effective way to convert video files for Youtube and Davinci Resolve. If you want to convert more than one video files a Bash script is very useful.
Let’s create a converting script
I am not a programmer but some times I need to create some scripts. So the script which we will create can be different that we create.
First, we need to decide some variables:
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ffmpeg for Davinci Resolve</title>
      <link>./post/ffmpegresolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/ffmpegresolve/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Ffmpeg for Davinci Users Ffmpeg is one of the most amazing tool in Linux. Most of the time, I use it for converting video files for Davinci Resolve. But why I am converting files, let’s take a look at it.
Unfotunately Linux version of Davinci Resolve does not support mpeg4 or H264 files for video editing. So we have to convert these kind of files to DNXHD or PRORES. First of all we should install ffmpeg;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo V155-15api with CentOS</title>
      <link>./post/lenovo-v155-15api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/lenovo-v155-15api/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Lenovo V155-15api Last month, I was looking for a cheap laptop with good Gpu, Cpu and good amount of Ram. I searched on internet for a while, Ryzen models was looking good and I found Lenovo v155-15api on hepsiburada.com. It had Ryzen 3500U Apu with 12 GB ram.
Lenovo V155-15  My purpose was running Davinci Resolve and Blender 3D for video editing and 3D animations and my budget was very limited (around 500$) so I have decided to buy it.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my journey</title>
      <link>./post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/hello/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          My journey has begun in 1998. I had bought my first PC with Pentium 166mmx, 32 Mb Ram, 2 Gb Hdd etc.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>